<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="atom.xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://mfstack.com/blog</id>
    <title>MF Stack Blog</title>
    <updated>2025-02-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mfstack.com/blog"/>
    <subtitle>MF Stack Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://mfstack.com/img/favicon.ico</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing MF Stack - Enabling your Mutual Funds distribution online]]></title>
        <id>https://mfstack.com/blog/introducing-mf-stack-enabling-your-mutual-funds-distribution-online</id>
        <link href="https://mfstack.com/blog/introducing-mf-stack-enabling-your-mutual-funds-distribution-online"/>
        <updated>2025-02-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Launch your Mutual Fund Apps using MF Stack pre-built Web & Mobile applications in just a day!]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Launch your Mutual Fund Apps using MF Stack pre-built Web &amp; Mobile applications in just a day!</p>
<p>Once you get the Fintech Primitives API keys for backend transactions engine, plug it into MF Stack and get started with your online distribution of mutual funds.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="the-origin-of-mf-stack"><strong>The Origin of MF Stack</strong><a href="https://mfstack.com/blog/introducing-mf-stack-enabling-your-mutual-funds-distribution-online#the-origin-of-mf-stack" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to the-origin-of-mf-stack" title="Direct link to the-origin-of-mf-stack">​</a></h2>
<p>I recently obtained my ARN license and got empaneled with a few AMCs. As a newcomer to the Mutual Funds Distribution market, I wasn’t entirely sure what to do next. While several white-labeled systems and third-party platforms exist for onboarding investors and processing transactions, choosing the right one required careful consideration. After exploring my options, I identified two key factors that influenced my decision:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Selecting the right backend transaction engine.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Finding an affordable platform with essential features</strong>, especially as a new ARN holder with zero AUM.</li>
</ul>
<p>MF Stack was built to address these challenges, offering a seamless onboarding experience for Mutual Fund distributors, IFAs, fintechs, and AMCs. It enables ARN holders to start distributing Mutual Funds with a cost-effective and feature-rich platform.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="what-is-mf-stack">What is MF Stack?<a href="https://mfstack.com/blog/introducing-mf-stack-enabling-your-mutual-funds-distribution-online#what-is-mf-stack" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What is MF Stack?" title="Direct link to What is MF Stack?">​</a></h2>
<p>MF Stack is a pre-built solution that allows you to start initiating Mutual Fund orders for your investors. If you’re an MF distributor or an Independent Financial Advisor, you can use MF Stack to onboard investors and process transactions seamlessly.</p>
<p>For fintech companies, wealth management firms, or brokerage houses, MF Stack offers both ready-to-use solutions and customizable integrations tailored to your system.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="what-do-we-offer">What do we offer?<a href="https://mfstack.com/blog/introducing-mf-stack-enabling-your-mutual-funds-distribution-online#what-do-we-offer" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What do we offer?" title="Direct link to What do we offer?">​</a></h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Web &amp; Mobile Apps</strong> with hosted workflows</li>
<li><strong>Distributor Portal</strong> (Web &amp; Mobile) for KYC onboarding, transactions, and reports</li>
<li><strong>SDKs and Custom Solutions</strong> tailored to your specific needs</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="transactions-engine">Transactions Engine:<a href="https://mfstack.com/blog/introducing-mf-stack-enabling-your-mutual-funds-distribution-online#transactions-engine" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Transactions Engine:" title="Direct link to Transactions Engine:">​</a></h2>
<p>The core of MF Stack is its robust backend infrastructure. Built on Fintech Primitives APIs - which offers flexibility, maximum uptime, and exceptional customer support.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="why-mf-stack">Why MF Stack?<a href="https://mfstack.com/blog/introducing-mf-stack-enabling-your-mutual-funds-distribution-online#why-mf-stack" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Why MF Stack?" title="Direct link to Why MF Stack?">​</a></h2>
<p>MF Stack offers a comprehensive suite of solutions designed to streamline and enhance your mutual fund distribution efforts. Here’s why you should consider integrating MF Stack into your operations:</p>
<p><strong>Comprehensive Digital Platform</strong></p>
<p>MF Stack provides a robust digital platform that includes web and mobile applications, allowing you to manage investor onboarding, transactions, and reporting seamlessly. This ensures a smooth and efficient experience for both distributors and investors.</p>
<p><strong>Flexible Integration Options</strong></p>
<p>Whether you’re a fintech company, wealth management firm, brokerage house or independent distributors/IFAs, MF Stack offers flexible integration options. You can choose from pre-built solutions for quick deployment or opt for custom integrations tailored to your specific system requirements.</p>
<p><strong>Cost-Effective for New Distributors</strong></p>
<p>For new ARN holders with zero Assets Under Management (AUM), MF Stack provides an affordable platform rich in essential features. This enables you to start your mutual fund distribution journey without significant upfront costs.</p>
<p><strong>Advanced Features</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>MF Stack offers a range of advanced features, including:</li>
<li><strong>Investor Portfolio Management:</strong> Real-time insights into portfolios, investment tracking, and performance monitoring.</li>
<li><strong>Financial Planning Tools:</strong> Comprehensive tools for goal-based planning and retirement calculations.</li>
<li><strong>Risk Profiling:</strong> Smart risk assessment to generate risk scores and analyze portfolios.</li>
<li><strong>Mutual Fund Transactions:</strong> A complete platform to process orders, manage SIPs, and track investments with real-time updates.</li>
<li><strong>Digital KYC and Onboarding:</strong> Simplified digital onboarding with integrated verification systems.</li>
<li><strong>Security:</strong> Enterprise-grade security features, including two-factor authentication and encryption.</li>
</ul>
<p>By choosing MF Stack, you’re equipping your business with a scalable, efficient, and secure platform that caters to the evolving needs of mutual fund distribution.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Manasa Madapu</name>
            <uri>https://betalectic.com/</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>